

ALEJANDRO RITTA

UX DESIGNER

About Me

I'm a UX designer. I consider myself a technology enthusiast from an early age. I took my first steps into the new era of "multimedia" around 1995 with my first PC. That was the starting point for me to enter the beautiful world of technology. I've ventured through various areas, from working at a Help Desk service to reaching a Data Center, exploring algorithms and programming to some extent. However, something was missing... something that always caught my attention: design. I began to investigate and delve into what I'm truly passionate about, which is "user experience."



+1-484-5423215



tomasatr@gmail.com



Cordoba Argentina



www.alejandro-ritta.com

LANGUAGE

- Spanish
- English (medium)

EXPERTISE

- Design Skills
- Creativity
- Proactive
- Empathy and User Perspective
- Critical Thinking
- Project management

EXPERIENCE

DevMagister New Jersey - USA 2022 - 2023

User experience designer, I have worked on web design projects for companies and organizations. My main tasks were user research, writer and prototyping on Figma.

Free Lancer

2022 - Present

I have worked on an ecommerce store project, designing the user interface using Elementor and configuring the Woocommerce payment platform.

Telecom Argentina 2010 - 2020

In almost my 10 years in the company, I worked in the Data center sector as a NOC operator, then I participated in some system design projects for monitoring the temperature and humidity of the racks, I also worked as IT support

EDUCATION

Google Certification

UX Design 2023

UTN University

Systems Engineering 2021-present

Universidad Santo Domingo Argentins

Design Systems 2009 - 2014

SKILLS SUMMARY

Design Process
99%
Figma
95%
Adobe XD
90%
Agile methodology
User Research
90%
Justinmind
80%